

Olegario Castellanos Guzmán

Birthdate: March 17th 1989 Mobile: (+521) 55-27-11-9309 Marital Status: Married

Email: olegario.castellanos@gmail.com

Skype: gary19890317

Address: A la sierra 128 Prados Vallarta, Zapopan Jalisco México.

Profile:

Software Engineer with over 6 years of experience in IT industry. Successfully architected/designed/led/developed enterprise projects covering various aspects of software development, processes and methodology.

Extensive experience in OOP development, JEE, middleware and enterprise application architecture and implementation. Ability to see, suggest, model and deliver viable technical solutions for real world business problems.

Over 6 years of experience in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) which includes User Interaction, Business Analysis/Modeling, Design/Architect, Development, Integration, Planning and management of Builds, Configuration, Code Management, Production/Customer Support, Maintenance, Enhancements and Quality Control, Testing, Implementation, Documentation, in Finance, Banking, Government, Custom Business Solutions domains.

Main Skills:

- Java / JEE 1.6
- Spring MVC / Hibernate
- HTML / JavaScript / CSS3
- UML 2.0
- Web Services [JAX-WS, JAX-RS and Axis2]

Secondary Skills:

- .NET (C#)
- Android
- Python

Languages

Spanish: Native language

English: Intermediate (speaking, reading, writing)

Academic background:

- 2003 2006 Centro de Bachillerato Tecnológico Industrial y de Servicios No. 91
 Technical Degree: Computer Information Science.
- 2006 2011 Universidad del Istmo Campus Ixtepec.
 Bachelor's Degree Computer Information Science
 Professional License.

Certifications:

Oracle Certified Professional Java Programmer 6 (OCPJP6)

Oracle Certified Expert Web Services Developer 6 (OCEWSD6)

Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)

Scrum Master Certified (SMC)

Professional Experience:

USAA [HCL] Banking

Java Software Engineer

December 2016-Present

- Analysis of functional requirements
- Technical support in production environment
- Problem solving, issue tracking and report incidents
- · Web services with JAX-WS and JAX-RS

Technical Proficiency:

- WebSphere Application Server 8.5
- Web Services JAX-WS, JAXB, XSD, XML y WSDL
- Oracle 11g and DB2
- Rational Software Architect
- EJB 3, JPA 2 and MDB
- Rational Team Concert (RTC)
- ODM 8.5 (Operational Decision Manager)

Walmart [Intellego] Software Factory

Java Software Engineer

July 2015 - December 2016

- Managed a team of 7 people for the project, created the estimations for efforts required to
 produce end to end solution and led the technical solution development. Responsible for the
 code reviews and code optimization in order to deliver the code as per the company quality
 standards.
- Architectural design to Enterprise Components.
- Provide technical support to team members and members of other departments integral to the successful completion of modules.
- Imparted technical direction and guidance to the development team to create designs, develop systems, resolve issues and manage development schedule.
- Design and implement an infrastructure that was structured to allow for consistent and repeatable patterns for building components to support new and existing business functions.
- Prepared detailed specifications from which programs will be written, designed, coded, tested and debugged. Developed RESTful web services that can support high-volume transactions.
- Performed requirement and system analysis, and Java web application development leadership.
- Use of Jenkins as continue integration tool

Technical Proficiency:

- WebSphere Application Server 7 & 8
- WSRR (WebSphere Repository and Registry)
- · Web Services JAX-WS, JAXB, XSD, XML and WSDL
- Oracle 11g
- GIT/SVN as version control system

ScotiaBank México [LATBC] Banking

Java / AIX Developer

November 2014 - July 2015

- Technical documentation.
- Design web pages with JSF 2.0
- Web services development web with JAX-WS
- Best design pattern on software development.
- SQL programming, Stored Procedures using Oracle 9i/10g, Sybase
- Batch AIX process
- UML Diagrams (Classes, Sequence, Activity and Package)
- Web Page with XHTML and ManageBeans
- · Quality insurance of code with FORTIFY

Technical Proficiency:

- JSF 2.0 WebSphere Application Server 7 and 8
- Web Services JAX-WS, JAXB, XSD, XML and WSDL
- HTML, JavaScript and CSS3
- XML and XSD
- Sybase 15
- MyEclipse 8.6
- AIX 6.1
- JDBC 3

SAT [Tecnides/Indra] Tax Collector

Java Developer

May 2014 - November 2014

- Development of enterprise component with JSF 2
- Design of XHTML pages and ManageBeans classes
- Installation and Configuration of WebLogic(WL) 11gR1
- Data Sources configuration on WL
- · Deployment of EJB on Application Server
- Activities, classes y sequence diagrams with UML 2.0
- Unit Test with JUnit / Mockito
- Quality code with SONAR, best practices code and fixed issues.

Technical Proficiency:

- JSF 2.0 WebLogic 11gR1
- Web Services JAX-WS, JAXB, XSD, XML and WSDL
- Maven and Sonar
- Oracle9i Enterprise Edition Release 9.2.0.8.0 64bit Production
- EJB 3 / JPA 2 and Hibernate 4
- Primefaces 3.5
- XML and XSD
- UML 2.0 (Start UML)
- JUnit and Mockito

ScotiaBank México [Tata Consultancy Services] Banking

Java Developer

March 2013 - April 2014

- · Abstracts specification and translated code.
- Test manager on performance application.
- Development on JEE Layer (front-end, web tier, services tier).
- JUnit on web services.

Technical Proficiency:

- JSF 2.0 WebSphere Application Sever 7.0, 8.0, 8.5
- Web Services JAX-WS, JAXB, XSD, XML y WSDL
- Ant
- JUnit
- Sybase 15, DB2
- JDBC 3.0
- Java Security

ScotiaBank [Tata Consultancy Services] Banking

.NET Developer

January 2013 - March 2013

- · Analysis and requirement design.
- Development of XSD and WSDL for top-down model.
- Design and development of unitary test with JUnit

Technical Proficiency:

- SOAP UI
- XML, WSDL and XSD
- Sybase 15
- IIS 7
- Visual Studio 2010

AXA Seguros [IDS Comercial] Insurance

Java Developer

April 2012 - November 2012

- Maintaining web page on intranet environment, application based on icefaces.
- Maintaining Web services built on Axis2 and stored procedure on Oracle 10g
- Design and development of unitary test with JUnit.
- Technical documentation

Technical Proficiency:

- Web Services Axis2
- XML, XSD and WSDL
- Oracle 10g
- JRules
- Ant, JSF 2
- Primefaces
- WebSphere Application Server 6 and 7
- EJB/Hibernate 3
- SOA & SOAP
- JDBC 3

ScotiaBank México [IDS Comercial] Banking

Java Developer

September 2011 – April 2012

- Maintaining web page based on JSF.
- · Coding of batch process on AIX.
- Development Task with Quartz running on AIX Operative System.
- Development of unitary test with JUnit.
- Technical documentation

Technical Proficiency:

- Web Services JAX-WS, JAXB, XML and XSD
- Ant
- JDBC / DB2
- WebSphere Application Server 7.0